Yumi's Cells 2
유미의 세포들 2
Episode 07 Heart Fever time
07화 심장열 시간
Look at this. Look.
이것 좀 보세요. 바라보다.
Her body is really amazing.
그녀의 몸매는 정말 놀랍습니다.
If you see her in person, she looks even more glamorous. She's really the best out of all my friends.
직접 보면 그녀는 더욱 글래머러스해 보인다. 그 사람은 내 친구들 중에 정말 최고예요.
She got street casted several times.
그녀는 여러 번 길거리 캐스팅을 받았습니다.
- Really? - Yes.
- 정말? - 예.
How is her body like that? What does she do? Is she a Pilates instructor?
그 사람 몸이 어때요? 그녀는 무엇을 하나요? 그 사람 필라테스 강사야?
- A pharmacist. - A Pharmacist?
- 약사. - 약사요?
Yes.
예.
- She's a pharmacist and her body is like that? - And her personality is really good.
- 약사인데 몸이 저래요? - 그리고 성격도 정말 좋아요.
She's my friend, but it's really annoying.
그 사람 내 친구인데 정말 짜증나네요.
I really struggled a lot to do my best in trying to put a good-looking man and woman together.
저는 잘생긴 남자와 여자를 하나로 묶어보려고 정말 노력을 많이 했어요.
Yeah, she would look good with Assistant Manager Ba Bi. I can see it.
네, 바비 대리랑 잘 어울릴 것 같아요. 나는 그것을 볼 수 있다.
- You can, right? - Yes.
- 그럴 수 있죠? - 예.
- Do you think it will work out well?
- 잘 될 것 같나요?
Assistant Manager Ba Bi's ex-girlfriend was a reporter.
바비 대리의 전 여자친구는 기자였다.
I saw her on the news a few times. She's pretty and so smart.
나는 그녀를 뉴스에서 몇 번 봤습니다. 그녀는 예쁘고 똑똑해요.
Yeah, if he can't date because he can't forget his ex, then this will do it.
네, 전 애인을 잊어버릴 수 없어서 데이트를 할 수 없다면, 이것으로 충분합니다.
Exactly, that's why I did my best.
바로 그렇기 때문에 나는 최선을 다했다.
Why do you need to work so hard? It's Ba Bi's business to take care of.
왜 그렇게 열심히 일해야 합니까? 돌보는 것은 Ba Bi의 일입니다.
But he hasn't.
하지만 그는 그렇지 않았습니다.
It's a waste of national resources to have such a good-looking guy be single.
이렇게 잘생긴 남자를 독신으로 두는 것은 국가적 자원 낭비다.
For the future of our country, I'm going to keep trying to set him up until it works.
우리나라의 미래를 위해, 효과가 있을 때까지 계속해서 그를 세우려고 노력할 것입니다.
Hey, what the heck. Th-that's her.
이봐, 대체 뭐야? 그- 그 사람이 바로 그 사람이에요.
Oh, you're right. The reporter.
아, 당신 말이 맞아요. 기자.
When we use and throw away a paper cup,
종이컵을 사용하고 버릴 때
one of the most commonly used convenience items, it results in a 7 g carbon footprint.
가장 일반적으로 사용되는 편의 품목 중 하나인 이 제품은 7g의 탄소 발자국을 발생시킵니다.
Fossil fuels are used in the process of producing and distributing paper cups...
종이컵을 생산하고 유통하는 과정에서 화석연료가 사용되는데...
See, she is both intelligent and beautiful, like your friend.
보세요, 그녀는 당신의 친구처럼 똑똑하고 아름답습니다.
It's exactly Yu Ba Bi's type. Hey, I think it's going to work out well.
딱 유바비 타입이에요. 아, 내 생각엔 잘 될 것 같아.
- I just got the feeling. - You just got it?
- 방금 느낌이 왔어. - 방금 알았어?
Just got the feeling?
방금 느낌이 들었나요?
Ruby, that girl... seriously.
루비, 그 여자... 정말요.
She's completely useless in life. She just chooses to do things she shouldn't do.
그녀는 인생에서 전혀 쓸모가 없습니다. 그녀는 단지 하지 말아야 할 일을 선택했을 뿐입니다.
What kind of enemy did Yumi lose to in a previous life?
유미는 전생에 어떤 적에게 졌나요?
What did Ruby do wrong?
루비가 무슨 잘못을 했나요?
Yeah, Ruby did nothing wrong. Actually, this is all...
응, 루비는 잘못한 게 없어. 사실 이게 다...
Love's fault!
사랑의 잘못!
I will walk you home.
집까지 데려다줄게
- No, it's okay. - It's on the way.
- 아뇨, ​​괜찮아요. - 가는 중이에요.
Assistant Manager Ba Bi.
바비 대리.
Let's...
해보자...
be friends.
친구가 되십시오.
I want us to be good friends.
나는 우리가 좋은 친구가 되기를 바랍니다.
It's because Love said we should be friends at that moment.
러브는 그 순간 우리가 친구가 되어야 한다고 말했기 때문이다.
What do you mean friends?!
친구란 무슨 뜻인가요?!
Ba Bi is going on a blind date because she said that nonsense!
바비가 그런 말도 안되는 소리를 해서 소개팅을 하게 됐어요!
If you're not going to date, then you should draw the line. What are you supposed to do?
데이트를 하지 않을 거라면 선을 그어야 합니다. 당신은 무엇을 해야 합니까?
They could just date, why draw the line?
그냥 데이트만 하면 되는데 왜 선을 그어?
The one who had the hardest time after breaking up with Wung is you, Sensitivity!
웅이와 헤어지고 가장 힘들었던 건 바로 당신, 감성!
Every night you used to drink and sing. Did you already forget?
매일 밤 당신은 술을 마시고 노래를 부르곤 했어요. 벌써 잊으셨나요?
I did but Ba Bi made me forget it.
그랬는데 바비 때문에 잊어버리게 됐어요.
Only Ba Bi can make me forget.
오직 바비만이 나를 잊게 할 수 있어요.
Ba Bi is the only answer! So why, why, why not?
바비만이 답이다! 그렇다면 왜, 왜, 왜 안되겠습니까?
- I really need to quit drinking coffee. - How can you quit?
- 정말 커피를 끊어야겠어요. - 어떻게 그만둘 수 있나요?
- My skin is dry. - No, it's not. It's nice.
- 피부가 건조해요. - 아니, 그렇지 않아요. 좋네요.
Are you coming back from lunch?
점심 먹고 돌아오나요?
- Assistant Manager Ba Bi. - Did you have lunch?
- 바비 대리. - 점심 먹었어?
Yes, I did.
네, 그랬어요.
My friend said she is really looking forward to it.
내 친구는 정말 기대된다고 하더군요.
You two take care of the location.
너희 둘이서 위치를 잘 살펴라.
But my friend said Gangnam Station is more convenient.
그런데 친구는 강남역이 더 편하다고 하더군요.
I see. Okay.
알겠어요. 좋아요.
BB fighting!
BB 화이팅!
What the heck.
대체 뭐야?
I'm annoyed. Why am I so annoyed?
짜증이 난다. 내가 왜 그렇게 짜증이 나는 걸까?
Assistant Manager Yumi.
유미 대리.
Yes?
예?
Can you come to the conference room for a moment to talk about the revisions?
개정안에 대해 잠시 논의하기 위해 회의실에 오실 수 있습니까?
Yes.
예.
This section only appeals to teenagers, so if we could change it to standard language...
이 섹션은 청소년에게만 해당되므로 표준 언어로 변경할 수 있다면...
- Sensitivity: Let's tell him not to go on the blind date. - Reason: Are you crazy?
- 감수성 : 소개팅을 하지 말라고 하자. - 이유 : 미쳤어?
Sensitivity: Tell him we didn't mean it and that the truth is Yumi also likes Ba Bi.
민감성: 진심이 아니었다고, 사실은 유미도 바비를 좋아한다고 말해주세요.
Reason: Are you crazy?
이유 : 미쳤어?
Sensitivity: A person's feelings can change. We can just say we were flustered because of the sudden confession.
민감성: 사람의 감정은 변할 수 있습니다. 갑작스러운 고백에 당황했다고 할 수 있겠네요.
- Sensitivity: That's the truth. - Reason: Are you joking?
- 감수성 : 그게 사실이에요. - 이유 : 농담하는 건가요?
Sensitivity: I can't watch Yu Ba Bi meet that glamorous pharmacist!
감성: 유바비가 그 매력적인 약사를 만나는 걸 볼 수가 없어요!
Assistant Manager Yumi?
대리 유미?
Reason: Yumi.
이유: 유미.
- Yes? - Did you hear what I just said?
- 예? - 내가 방금 한 말 들었어?
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
- I see you were thinking of something else. - Uh, no...
- 뭔가 다른 생각을 하고 있던 것 같군요. - 어, 아니...
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
What were you thinking about?
무슨 생각을 하고 있었나요?
It's now. Let's tell him now.
지금이다. 지금 그에게 말해보자.
That's enough!
그거면 충분해요!
But do you guys remember?
그런데 여러분, 기억하시나요?
Babi threw away the couple ring he wore with his ex
바비가 전 애인과 끼고 있던 커플링을 버렸어요
without a second thought.
아무 생각 없이.
- That's right. He did. - Like that?
- 좋아요. 그는 그랬다. - 그런가요?
That kind of personality is endlessly sweet but once it's over, he's the type that doesn't even look back.
그런 성격은 한없이 다정하지만 한번 지나면 뒤도 돌아보지 않는 타입이다.
I think he already gave up on Yumi.
내 생각엔 그는 이미 유미를 포기한 것 같아요.
The moment they said she said be friends, it was over.
그녀가 친구가 되라고 말한 순간 그것은 끝났습니다.
- Yeah, that's right. - What do you mean? We haven't even tried telling him yet.
- 네, 맞아요. - 무슨 뜻이에요? 우리는 아직 그에게 말하려고 시도조차 하지 않았습니다.
You can tell me. Don't you like the revisions?
당신은 나에게 말할 수 있습니다. 개정판이 마음에 들지 않나요?
No.
아니요.
I will think about it a bit.
좀 생각해 보겠습니다.
I think the answer will come out if I think about it.
생각해보면 답이 나올 것 같아요.
Then, will you?
그럼, 그럴래?
Yes.
예.
Still, it would be nice if he didn't go on the blind date.
그래도 소개팅만 안 했으면 좋았을 텐데.
Day of Yu Ba Bi's blind date.
유바비 소개팅의 날.
Saturday night 7:55 pm.
토요일 밤 7시 55분.
There's no better time to text with your boyfriend or guy you like.
당신의 남자친구나 당신이 좋아하는 남자와 문자를 보내기에 이보다 더 좋은 시간은 없습니다.
Did you get home all right?
집에 잘 도착하셨나요?
- Have a good night. - Have a good weekend.
- 좋은 밤 되세요. - 좋은 주말 보내세요.
Although the words are meaningless in life
그 말은 인생에서는 의미가 없지만
they are the world's sweetest words.
세상에서 가장 감미로운 말이에요.
How long has it been since we sent those kinds of texts on a Saturday night?
토요일 밤에 이런 문자를 보낸지 얼마나 됐나요?
Yet Yu Ba Bi, who went on a blind date, is probably
그런데 소개팅을 한 유바비는 아마도
exchanging useless but sweet texts with her by now, right?
지금쯤 그녀와 쓸데없는 달콤한 문자를 주고받고 있지 않나요?
Damn it.
젠장.
- Sensitivity. - What?
- 감도. - 무엇?
Yumi says to please shut up.
유미는 조용히 하라고 말한다.
Will you shut up?! That guy... really!
닥쳐줄래?! 그 사람... 정말이에요!
It would be nice if I could sleep early on a day like today.
오늘 같은 날에는 일찍 잠을 잘 수 있으면 좋을 것 같아요.
But I'm not sleepy.
하지만 나는 졸리지 않습니다.
♫ Sweet cologne, truth be told ♫
♫ 달콤한 향수, 사실대로 말하면 ♫
♫ Truth be told ♫
♫ 진실을 말해주세요 ♫
♫ You and I, ♫
♫ 당신과 나, ♫
♫  are walking on the same path♫
♫ 같은 길을 걷고 있어요♫
♫ When this night passes  ♫
♫ 이 밤이 지나면 ♫
♫ Oh, we'll know  ♫
♫ 아, 우리가 알게 될 거야 ♫
♫ Oh, we'll know,  ♫
♫ 아, 우리가 알게 될 거야, ♫
♫ At sunrise ♫
♫ 해가 뜰 때 ♫
♫ You and I ♫
♫ 당신과 나 ♫
I fell asleep.
나는 잠들었다.
What time is it now?
지금은 몇시입니까?
New Message from Assistant Manager Yu Ba Bi
유바비 대리의 새 메시지
What's this? We got a text from Yu Babi?
이건 뭐죠? 유바비한테 문자 왔어?
Assistant Manager Yumi I want to return your umberella.
대리 유미 당신의 우산을 돌려주고 싶어요.
Can I come by your place for a moment?
잠시 당신 집에 들러도 될까요?
What is this? What is this all of a sudden?
이게 뭔가요? 갑자기 이게 무슨 소리야?
- It's Ba Bi! - It's a text from Ba Bi!
- 바비예요! - 바비가 보낸 문자예요!
Ba Bi? Really?
바비? 정말?
He's coming by?
그 사람이 올 거야?
What is this? What is he saying all of a sudden?
이게 뭔가요? 그 사람 갑자기 무슨 말을 하는 거야?
He's asking if he can come by my place? Now?
그 사람이 내 집에 올 수 있는지 물어보는 거에요? 지금?
Let's all shout together!
모두 함께 외쳐보자!
You can come! You can come!
오시면 됩니다! 오시면 됩니다!
You can come!
오시면 됩니다!
When did he send this?
그 사람이 이걸 언제 보냈어요?
8:59 pm. What's the time now?
오후 8시 59분. 지금은 몇 시야?
2:20... in the morning.
2시 20분... 새벽.
2:22 in the morning?!
새벽 2시 22분?!
Are you saying we were sleeping?
우리 자고 있었단 말야?
Are you saying we didn't see Ba Bi's text because we were sleeping?!
자느라 바비 문자를 못봤다는 겁니까?!
He's saying we weren't able to reply because we were sleeping until 2 am?!
새벽 2시까지 자서 답장을 못했다고?!
Hey! We can just send a reply now.
여기요! 이제 답장을 보내면 됩니다.
- Yeah! - Let's send it!
- 응! - 보내자!
It's 2 in the morning. Are you guys crazy?
새벽 2시입니다. 너희들 미쳤어?
Even if it's 2 am, we can't just go to sleep.
새벽 2시가 되어도 우리는 잠을 잘 수 없습니다.
I'm just now seeing your message because I fell asleep.
잠들었기 때문에 지금 막 당신의 메시지를 보고 있어요.
You can return my umbrella later.
나중에 내 우산을 반납해도 됩니다.
Have a good night.
좋은 밤 되세요.
I tried waving my hand at a bus that has already left.
이미 떠난 버스를 향해 손을 흔들어 보았습니다.
I am always like this.
나는 항상 이렇습니다.
Always a step late.
항상 한발 늦습니다.
Yumi, look at that!
유미, 저것 좀 봐!
Yu Ba Bi isn't asleep.
유바비가 잠이 안 와요.
He's writing a reply.
그 사람이 답장을 쓰고 있어요.
He's not asleep at this hour.
그는 이 시간에 잠을 자지 않습니다.
And on the day of his blind date.
그리고 소개팅 당일.
And it's a very long reply.
그리고 답변이 너무 깁니다.
If it's this long, it'll probably be over 100 characters.
이 정도 길면 아마도 100자 이상은 될 것 같습니다.
Okay, when I count to three,
좋아요, 셋까지 셀 때,
we will all shout "Oh yay!" together.
우리 모두는 "오 예!"라고 외칠 것입니다. 함께.
Oh yay!
아 예!
- Guys, would you just please calm down? - Shout loudly.
- 얘들아, 좀 진정 좀 해줄래? - 큰 소리로 외쳐보세요.
One, two...
하나, 둘...
Guys, we're in trouble. Ba Bi deleted whatever he was typing.
여러분, 우리는 곤경에 빠졌습니다. 바비는 자신이 입력하던 내용을 모두 삭제했습니다.
- What! - No!
- 무엇! - 아니요!
Where did it go?
어디로 갔나요?
Why did he stop writing? He was writing something till just now.
그는 왜 글쓰기를 중단했나요? 그는 지금까지 무언가를 쓰고 있었습니다.
What's going on? Why did he stop writing?
무슨 일이야? 그는 왜 글쓰기를 중단했나요?
Does that mean he's coming right now? Or was it the result of his blind date today?
그 사람이 지금 온다는 뜻인가요? 아니면 오늘 소개팅의 결과였나요?
Perhaps a confession that he was reminded of Yumi more because he went on a blind date?
소개팅을 해서 유미가 더 생각났다는 고백이 아닐까?
I am dying of curiosity. What did he write and then delete?!
나는 호기심에 죽어가고 있다. 그는 무엇을 썼다가 지웠는가?!
He was writing something and he deleted it!
그는 뭔가를 쓰고 있었는데 그것을 삭제했습니다!
Can't we ask what he wrote?
그가 무엇을 썼는지 물어보면 안 되나요?
Are you guys crazy? How can we ask something like that?
너희들 미쳤어? 우리가 어떻게 그런 걸 물어볼 수 있나요?
Why can't you? You coward!
왜 할 수 없습니까? 겁쟁이야!
- Why is that being a coward– - Hey!
- 그게 왜 겁쟁이야? - 이봐!
- Yu Ba Bi started to type something again. - What?
- 유바비가 다시 뭔가를 타이핑하기 시작했어요. - 무엇?
Yes, Yu Ba Bi. Anything is fine so just type!
응, 유바비. 무엇이든 괜찮으니 그냥 입력하세요!
And I'll show you why we're the Yu Ba Bi club!
그리고 왜 우리가 유바비클럽인지 알려드릴게요!
Are you free tomorrow morning?
내일 아침에 시간 있어요?
Wow! He wants to meet!
우와! 그는 만나고 싶어합니다!
- Before Yu Ba Bi changes his mind and says something else, let's hurry and nail it in. - Okay!
- 유바비가 마음 변해서 다른 말 하기 전에 빨리 짚어보자. - 알았어!
Stay right there! Nail in our plans! Bang Bang!
거기 그대로 있어! 우리 계획대로 하세요! 뱅뱅!
The skill of immediately accepting someone's suggested plan
누군가가 제안한 계획을 즉시 받아들이는 기술
and nailing it in so that they cannot change their mind.
마음이 바뀌지 않도록 고정시키는 거죠.
Ah, yes. It's fine by me. At what time should we meet then?
아, 그렇죠. 나는 괜찮습니다. 그럼 우리 몇 시에 만나야 할까요?
Is ten o'clock okay? Should we meet in front of that café nearby your place?
10시 괜찮나요? 우리 집 근처 그 카페 앞에서 만날까?
Yes, that's fine.
네, 괜찮습니다.
This is the first time Ba Bi asked us to meet first since that day, right?
바비가 그 날 이후로 우리에게 먼저 만나자고 한 건 처음이겠죠?
He can return the umbrella at work, but if he insists.
그는 직장에 우산을 반납할 수 있지만, 그가 주장하는 경우에는 가능합니다.
This is our last chance. It's really the last.
이번이 마지막 기회입니다. 정말 마지막이에요.
If we waste this chance like a fool again, then our relationship with Ba Bi
또 바보처럼 기회를 놓치면 바비와의 관계는
will end as being friends forever.
영원히 친구로 남을 것이다.
Sensitivity, should Yumi do an effortless look?
감성, 유미는 여유로운 표정을 해야 할까?
No. Let's not do an effortless look.
아니, 애쓰지 말자.
This time, do everything that you can do.
이번에는 할 수 있는 모든 것을 해보세요.
♫ To the point where there's no gap ♫
♫ 빈틈이 없을 정도로 ♫
♫ Fill me up fully with you ♫
♫ 나를 너로 가득 채워줘 ♫
♫ Cause you're beautiful ♫
♫ 당신은 아름다우니까요 ♫
♫ As much as I can't even breathe ♫
♫ 숨이 막힐 정도로 ♫
♫ I'm falling for you ♫
♫ 난 너에게 반해버렸어 ♫
♫ When I fall in love with you ♫
♫ 내가 당신과 사랑에 빠졌을 때 ♫
Moisturize. Shine. Let's do it all.
보습. 빛나는. 다 해보자.
♫ You're there, Oh ♫
♫ 거기 있구나, 오 ♫
♫ I have something to tell you  ♫
♫ 당신에게 할 말이 있어요 ♫
♫  I want to carefully come up to you ♫
♫ 조심스럽게 다가가고 싶어 ♫
♫ and whisper ♫
♫ 그리고 속삭임 ♫
Assistant Manager Ba Bi.
바비 대리.
Oh, hello.
아, 안녕하세요.
You're early.
일찍 왔네요.
Please stop. Please just calm down!
그만하세요. 제발 진정하세요!
Bang. Bang. Bang. Bang. Bang. Bang.
쾅. 쾅. 쾅. 쾅. 쾅. 쾅.
- Guys, just so you know, Yu Babi went on a blind date yesterday and - Bang. Bang.
- 여러분, 유바비가 어제 소개팅을 했고, - 쾅. 쾅.
- we don't know the outcome yet. - Bang. Bang. Bang.
- 결과는 아직 알 수 없습니다. - 쾅. 쾅. 쾅.
He might have wanted to return the umbrella quickly because he just felt uncomfortable!
그냥 불편해서 빨리 우산을 돌려주고 싶었을 수도 있겠네요!
What do you think? Is your heart still pounding?
어떻게 생각하나요? 아직도 심장이 뛰나요?
Bang. Bang. Bang. Bang. Bang. Bang. Bang.
쾅. 쾅. 쾅. 쾅. 쾅. 쾅. 쾅.
- You guys seriously! - Bang. Bang. Bang. Bang.
- 여러분, 진심이에요! - 쾅. 쾅. 쾅. 쾅.
- Here's your umbrella. - Thanks.
- 여기 우산 있어요. - 감사해요.
But it seems like you have plans today.
그런데 오늘은 계획이 있는 것 같군요.
Ah, I had to go stop by somewhere in the morning.
아, 아침에 어딘가에 들러야 했어요.
- I see. It's ten o'clock now, where did you... - Ah...
- 알겠어요. 지금 10시인데 어디갔어... - 아...
BABI
바비
You should have said you have plans after. How can you say that you came after dropping by somewhere?
나중에 계획이 있다고 말했어야 했는데. 어디 들렀다가 왔다고 어떻게 말할 수 있나요?
Stupid! If we have plans after, we have to part ways immediately!
멍청한! 나중에 계획이 있으면 바로 헤어져야 해요!
Can't you think?
생각할 수 없나요?
Getting this dressed up to get an umbrella on a Sunday morning.
일요일 아침에 우산을 가지려고 옷을 차려입는 것입니다.
It's so ridiculous!
정말 말도 안돼!
Shut up!
입 다물어!
I'm going to get going then.
그럼 바로 갈게요.
- Are you busy? - What?
- 바쁘세요? - 무엇?
No. I'm on my way to exercise in the park.
아니요. 공원에 운동하러 가는 중이에요.
Ah, then take a coffee with you. I'll buy it.
아, 그럼 커피 한잔 같이 드세요. 나는 그것을 살 것이다.
You're going to buy?
당신은 살 예정입니까?
Of course, I should buy. What do you want to have?
물론 사야죠. 무엇을 갖고 싶나요?
Cafe mocha.
카페모카.
Okay.
좋아요.
I'm going!
나는 간다!
BABI
바비
Wait a minute!
잠깐 기다려요!
Stop. It's still a red light.
멈추다. 아직은 빨간불이에요.
We still don't know the outcome of Yu Ba Bi's blind date.
유바비의 소개팅 결과는 아직 알려지지 않았습니다.
If things are going well with Ruby's friend, what are you going to do, you wild girl?
루비 친구랑 잘 지내면 어떡할 거야, 이 사나운 여자야?
Now that you mention it, you're right.
이제 언급하신 것이 맞습니다.
Let's find out how the blind date went first.
먼저 소개팅이 어떻게 진행됐는지 알아보겠습니다.
Fishing cell, help us.
낚시 셀, 도와주세요.
I need you to hook me Yu Ba Bi's blind date outcome.
유바비 소개팅 결과를 낚아주세요.
Here you go.
여기요.
I guess even now you still exercise on weekends.
내 생각엔 지금도 여전히 주말에 운동을 하시는 것 같아요.
No, I haven't been able to these days.
아니요, 요즘은 못 했어요.
I'm coming out for the first time in a long time.
오랜만에 처음으로 나오네요.
Then what do you do on the weekends when you don't exercise?
그렇다면 운동하지 않는 주말에는 무엇을 하시나요?
Strangely these days, there are a lot of family events
요즘 이상하게 가족행사가 많아
and friends' weddings too.
그리고 친구들의 결혼식도요.
Sensitivity: Yesterday, yesterday, you had a blind date.
감수성: 어제, 어제 소개팅을 했습니다.
Yesterday I went on a blind date.
어제는 소개팅에 나갔습니다.
That's right. You said you were going on a blind date.
좋아요. 소개팅을 한다고 하더군요.
Yes.
예.
Sensitivity: So? So what happened?
민감도: 그래서요? 그래서 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
I guess you don't come out to exercise these days, Assistant Manager Yumi?
요즘 운동하러 안 나오시나봐요 유미 대리님?
Right. I also haven't been able to come out these days.
오른쪽. 저도 요즘에는 나오지 못했어요.
Writer: Why did you stop talking about it? If you brought it up, you should come to a conclusion!
작성자: 왜 그 얘기를 그만 두셨나요? 제기했다면 결론을 내려야합니다!
Sensitivity: What happened?
민감성: 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
Anxiety: It must be going well. Isn't that why he purposefully brought it up?
불안: 잘 되고 있을 거에요. 그래서 일부러 그런 얘기를 꺼낸 게 아닌가?
The weather is so nice today.
오늘 날씨가 너무 좋네요.
- It's perfect for exercising, right? - Yes.
- 운동하기 딱이죠? - 예.
Excuse me for a moment.
잠시 실례합니다.
Guard: No way it's the woman he went on a blind date with, right?
경비병 : 설마 그 사람과 소개팅을 했던 그 여자 맞죠?
Right?
오른쪽?
Anxiety: Is it really over then?
불안: 그럼 정말 끝난 걸까?
Two cafe mochas are ready.
카페모카 2개가 준비되어 있어요.
Sensitivity: I knew this would happen if we hesitated.
민감성: 망설이면 이런 일이 일어날 줄 알았습니다.
Here.
여기.
Ah, thank you.
아, 고마워요.
- If you aren't busy shall we stay here— - Let's leave.
- 바쁘지 않으면 여기 머물까— - 떠나자.
- What?
- 무엇?
Ah, yes, yes, let's leave.
아, 그래, 그래, 떠나자.
Then, where are you going?
그럼 어디로 가시나요?
I should get home.
집에 가야 해요.
Then, go ahead. Thanks for the coffee.
그럼 계속하세요. 커피 고마워요.
- No problem. Bye. - See you tomorrow.
- 괜찮아요. 안녕. - 내일 봐요.
Fashion: Is it over?
패션: 이제 끝났나요?
Guard: Did he really call us out just to return the umbrella?
경비병: 정말 우산을 돌려주려고 우리를 불렀나요?
- Face Wash-up: Ba Bi. - Sensitivity: Ba Bi... Are you really going?
- 세안: 바비. - 감성 : 바비... 정말 가시나요?
Anxiety: I guess he's really going.
불안: 정말 가고 있는 것 같아요.
Sensitivity: No, he's not going. He's not going.
민감도: 아니요, 그는 가지 않습니다. 그는 가지 않을 것이다.
Anxiety: Oh no.
불안: 아뇨.
Face Wash: What's going on?
세안: 무슨 일이에요?
Face Wash: Did we come out with pretty make-up on for this?
세안: 우리 이거 예쁜 화장하고 나왔나요?
Writer: Then what do you want to do? He's gone.
작가: 그러면 당신은 무엇을 하고 싶나요? 그는 사라졌습니다.
Fashion: We got dressed up like this in vain. Let's just go anywhere.
패션: 우리는 이렇게 차려입었지만 헛수고였습니다. 그냥 어디든 가자.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Are you busy, Eonni?
언니 바쁜가요?
No. Why?
아뇨. 왜요?
Eonni, do you perhaps know who Assistant Manager Ba Bi has feelings for?
언니 혹시 바비 대리님이 누구한테 마음이 있는지 아시나요?
He said there's someone and that he got rejected last time when we went out for drinks.
사람이 있는데 지난번에 술 마시러 갔을 때 거절당했다고 하더군요.
Do you know who that is?
그 사람이 누구인지 아시나요?
Uh, no.
어, 아니.
Do you not know? But you guys are close.
모르시나요? 하지만 너희들은 가깝다.
We aren't that close. And even if we were close, how would I know all that.
우리는 그다지 가깝지 않습니다. 그리고 우리가 친하다고 해도 그걸 어떻게 다 알겠어요.
But why are you asking that?
그런데 그걸 왜 묻는 걸까요?
Assistant Manager Ba Bi made plans with my friend for the blind date and then canceled them.
바비 대리는 친구와 소개팅 계획을 세웠다가 취소했다.
It's so ridiculous.
정말 우스꽝스럽습니다.
He cancelled?
그가 취소했다고요?
The date was yesterday night but he sent her a text that morning saying he was sorry
날짜는 어제 밤인데 그날 아침에 미안하다는 문자를 보냈어요
that something urgent came up.
급한 일이 생겼다고.
Yesterday I went on a blind date.
어제는 소개팅에 나갔습니다.
Didn't he go on the blind date yesterday?
그 사람 어제 소개팅에 가지 않았나요?
No. I'm telling you he didn't.
아뇨. 그가 그러지 않았다고 말씀드리고 싶습니다.
- Then— - So I called him and he apologized to me.
- 그러면— - 그래서 그 사람한테 전화했더니 그 사람이 나한테 사과했어요.
He said he wasn't ready yet.
그는 아직 준비가 안 됐다고 하더군요.
He said he couldn't go out with my friend because it didn't seem polite.
그 친구는 예의가 없는 것 같아서 친구랑 데이트를 할 수 없다고 하더군요.
It's so annoying.
너무 짜증나네요.
What kind of a woman is she that she sways Yu Ba Bi's heart like that?
어떤 여자가 유바비의 마음을 저렇게 흔드는 걸까요?
She's coming.
그녀가 온다.
She's totally upset because of Assistant Manager Ba Bi.
그녀는 바비 대리 때문에 완전히 화가 났다.
Eonni, I'm going to go. Let me know if you know anything.
언니, 나 갈게. 아는 것이 있으면 알려주세요.
Sure.
확신하는.
Did you hear that? He didn't go on the blind date.
그거 들었어? 그는 소개팅에 참석하지 않았습니다.
He didn't go on the blind date. He said he wasn't ready yet.
그는 소개팅에 참석하지 않았습니다. 그는 아직 준비가 안 됐다고 하더군요.
But he lied that he went on the blind date.
그런데 그 사람이 소개팅에 나갔다고 거짓말을 했어요.
- Why? - He thought
- 왜? - 그는 생각했다
Yumi would feel burdened.
유미는 부담감을 느꼈을 것이다.
He actually didn't want to.
그는 실제로 원하지 않았습니다.
It was like that.
그랬어요.
But he said that so that Yumi feels better.
그런데 유미가 기분이 좋아지려고 그런 말을 한 거예요.
Yumi asked him to be friends
유미가 그에게 친구가 되어달라고 부탁했어요
so he purposely drew the line?
그래서 일부러 선을 그은 걸까요?
- You're shining. - You're right.
- 당신은 빛나고 있어요. - 당신 말이 맞아요.
Bang. Bang. Bang. Bang. Bang.
쾅. 쾅. 쾅. 쾅. 쾅.
Bang. Bang. Bang. Bang.
쾅. 쾅. 쾅. 쾅.
What is this?
이게 뭔가요?
- Isn't this heart fever time? - What?
- 지금은 심장이 뜨거워지는 시기 아닌가요? - 무엇?
Yumi, go!
유미, 가!
We are going to Yu Ba Bi!
우리는 유바비로 갑니다!
Sensitivity finally exploded.
드디어 감도가 폭발했습니다.
Heart Fever Time - Sensitivity's ultra power to make Yumi fall in love even without Love.
Heart Fever Time - 사랑 없이도 유미를 사랑에 빠지게 만드는 감성의 초능력.
Excuse me, sorry to bother you.
죄송해요, 귀찮게 해서 미안해요.
Did you lose an umbrella?
우산을 잃어버렸나요?
You look pretty. Kim Yumi. I think you would do well.
당신은 예뻐 보인다. 김유미. 내 생각엔 당신이 잘할 것 같아요.
I think it sounds good.
제 생각엔 좋은 것 같아요.
Temporary state of emotional outburst. There's nothing you can't do when you enter this state.
일시적인 감정 폭발 상태. 이 상태에 들어가면 할 수 없는 일이 없습니다.
Yumi, run! Yumi, run!
유미, 달려라! 유미, 달려라!
Let's go! Yumi, run!
갑시다! 유미, 달려라!
Yumi, run!
유미, 달려라!
♫ and think about someone ♫
♫ 그리고 누군가에 대해 생각해 보세요 ♫
♫ Because in matter which had nothing to do with me ♫ Oh!
♫ 왜냐면 나와는 아무런 관련도 없는 일이니까 ♫ 아!
♫ I uselessly took an interest ♫
♫ 쓸데없이 관심을 가졌어 ♫
Damn it. I lost again.
젠장. 나는 또 졌다.
I lost again.
나는 또 졌다.
However, the difference from Love's power is that
그러나 사랑의 힘과의 차이점은
because it is temporary it doesn't last long.
일시적이기 때문에 오래 가지 않습니다.
But,
하지만
if I suddenly do this, won't he think I'm crazy?
내가 갑자기 이러면 그 사람은 내가 미쳤다고 생각하지 않을까?
He could have just not wanted to go on the blind date.
그는 소개팅에 가고 싶지 않았을 수도 있습니다.
Yes.
예.
This isn't it right.
이건 옳지 않아요.
You just rejected him. What are you trying to do now?
당신은 그를 거부했습니다. 지금 무엇을 하려고 하시나요?
Anyway, I almost became an idiot.
어쨌든 나는 거의 바보가 될 뻔했다.
So a year ago, that day when I looked back.
그래서 1년 전, 돌이켜보니 그날.
We still remember it. [Wedding]
우리는 아직도 그것을 기억합니다. [결혼식]
Yu Ba Bi & Kim In Yeong
유바비 & 김인영
Do you know
알고 계세요
that I ran to you, Yu Ba Bi, that day?
그날 내가 유바비한테 달려간 거?
Congratulations Assistant Manager Ba Bi.
바비 대리님 축하드립니다.
Hey, I'm jealous, you punk.
야, 질투난다, 이 새끼야.
Congratulations.
축하해요.
Ah, but this is really making me shy.
아, 그런데 정말 부끄럽네요.
Congratulations Manager Ba Bi.
바비 매니저님 축하드립니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Face Wash Up: I hate to even imagine something like that.
세안: 그런 일은 상상조차 하기 싫습니다.
So let's squeeze it out once more.
그럼 한번 더 짜봅시다.
Heart Fever Time!
심장 발열 시간!
♫ In the season which passes ♫
♫ 지나가는 계절에 ♫
♫ in the moment which stopped wordlessly ♫
♫말 없이 멈춘 순간에 ♫
♫ perhaps while looking at each other ♫
♫ 아마도 서로를 바라보면서 ♫
♫ will we hang on? ♫
♫ 우리 좀 더 버틸까? ♫
Excuse me. ♫ Although I am a little scared ♫
실례합니다. ♫ 조금은 겁이 나지만 ♫
♫ of this approaching day ♫
♫ 다가오는 날의 ♫
♫ If it happens will you say to me ♫
♫ 그런 일이 생기면 나에게 말해줄래 ♫
♫ "you did well" and "good job"? ♫
♫ "잘했어" 그리고 "수고했어"? ♫
Reason: But isn't this the same situation as before?
이유: 그런데 이건 예전과 똑같은 상황 아닌가요?
Watch out!
조심하세요!
Reason: This situation seems the same as the day Wu Gi rejected us.
이유: 이번 상황은 우기가 우리를 거절했던 날과 같은 상황인 것 같다.
Reason: It was the same back then. We misunderstood things and had the courage for nothing.
이유: 그때도 그랬어요. 우리는 일을 오해했고 괜히 용기를 냈습니다.
Then Seonbae...
그럼 선배는...
Yes?
예?
Do you want to go on a blind date?
소개팅을 하고 싶나요?
Reason: We just made memories that we wanted to forget.
이유: 그냥 잊고 싶은 추억을 만들었습니다.
That's right. Yes.
좋아요. 예.
Even the location
위치까지
Let's stop doing stupid things.
어리석은 짓은 그만하자.
How old are you now, Kim Yumi?
김유미 씨는 지금 몇 살이에요?
Assistant Manager Yumi?
대리 유미?
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
What?
무엇?
You said you were going home earlier.
집에 일찍 간다고 했잖아.
You didn't come out to exercise, right?
운동하러 나온 건 아니지?
Ah, the thing is...
아, 문제는...
We can't walk away now. It would be better
우리는 지금 떠날 수 없습니다. 더 좋을 것 같아요
to get rejected and die heroically.
거절당하고 영웅적으로 죽는 것.
I'll squeeze out the last bit of power.
마지막 남은 힘을 짜내겠습니다.
It's Heart Fever Time!
지금은 심장 발열 시간입니다!
- The thing is... - Yes.
- 문제는... - 네.
I have something to tell you.
당신에게 할 말이 있습니다.
To me?
나에게?
I also
나도
want to know more about you.
당신에 대해 더 알고 싶습니다.
What?
무엇?
I also
나도
like you.
당신처럼.
One week later
일주일 후
Ms. Kim Yumi.
김유미씨.
You eat healthily, you don't drink much as well.
당신은 건강하게 먹고, 술도 많이 마시지 않습니다.
I do have one or two cans of beer every week.
나는 매주 맥주 한두 캔을 마신다.
It's stress induced gastritis.
스트레스로 인한 위염입니다.
Recently, was something causing you a lot of stress?
최근에 스트레스를 많이 받는 일이 있었나요?
Take medicine for the time being and stop drinking coffee.
당분간 약을 드시고 커피도 마시지 마세요.
All right.
괜찮은.
Assistant Manager Yumi.
유미 대리.
- Yes. - Just a moment. - Sure.
- 예. - 잠시만요. - 확신하는.
I think you need to revise everything you did this morning.
오늘 아침에 한 모든 일을 다시 수정해야 할 것 같아요.
What? Everything?
무엇? 모든 것?
It's an introduction of the new product but a lot of keywords are missing.
신제품 소개인데 키워드가 많이 빠졌네요.
Ah, I see.
아, 그렇군요.
- I have marked the places that you have to revise so please refer to them. - Okay.
- 수정해야 할 부분을 표시해 두었으니 참고하시기 바랍니다. - 좋아요.
- Are you okay, Assistant Manager Yumi? - Pardon?
- 괜찮으세요, 유미 대리님? - 뭐라고요?
Just earlier, Assistant Manager Ba Bi was conveying exactly what the Department Head said during the meeting.
조금 전, 바비 대리는 회의에서 부서장이 말한 내용을 정확하게 전달하고 있었습니다.
It's not his opinion.
그것은 그의 의견이 아닙니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Just in case you misunderstand.
만약에 당신이 오해한 경우를 대비해.
Oh, no it's alright. I have to fix it if there's editing needed.
아뇨, 괜찮아요. 편집이 필요하면 수정해야 합니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Well, amongst the meeting schedules
그럼 회의 일정 중에
let me tell you.
내가 말해주지.
Oh, right. He said I can't drink coffee.
아, 그렇죠. 그는 내가 커피를 마실 수 없다고 말했다.
Do you know the colors?
색깔을 아시나요?
Yes.
예.
- Assistant Manager. - Yes?
- 대리. - 예?
I'm taking a look at it now. When should I have the editing done by?
지금 살펴보는 중이에요. 편집은 언제까지 완료해야 합니까?
Well, the sooner the better. Is it possible to do it by today?
글쎄, 빠를수록 좋습니다. 오늘까지 가능할까요?
- I'm going to have to. - Do as much as you can.
- 그래야 할 것 같아요. - 할 수 있는 만큼 하세요.
I'm sorry, I should have done well from the start.
미안해요, 처음부터 잘했어야 했는데.
- Did your hospital visit go well? - They said it's gastritis.
- 병원 방문은 잘 되셨나요? - 위염이라고 하더군요.
They say it's caused by stress
스트레스 때문에 그런다고 하네요
but I don't think I've been under a lot of stress recently.
그런데 최근에 스트레스를 많이 받은 적은 없는 것 같아요.
I think it's just because you often eat a lot of spicy food.
아무래도 매운 음식을 자주 먹어서 그런 것 같아요.
Did I do that?
내가 그랬나요?
Couldn't it be because you eat food that is too spicy?
너무 매운 음식을 먹어서 그런 것은 아닐까?
It could be.
그럴 수도 있습니다.
Figures. I ate spicy soup even for lunch.
피규어. 점심에도 매운탕을 먹었습니다.
See.
보다.
Hello! Ah, yes, yes. I'll send it to you now.
안녕하세요! 아, 그래, 그래. 지금 보내드리겠습니다.
What about medicine?
의학은 어떻습니까?
I took it.
나는 그것을 가져갔다.
Episode 08 Ba Bi's World
08화 바비의 세계
You all must remember the Gate of Heart, the only way to enter Yumi's village.
여러분 모두는 유미의 마을로 들어갈 수 있는 유일한 길인 마음의 문을 기억하셔야 합니다.
- It's a frog. - The Gate of Heart has a twenty-eight character password.
- 개구리예요. - 마음의 문에는 28자의 비밀번호가 있습니다.
If Wung's love cell disguised himself as a frog and entered,
웅의 연애 세포가 개구리로 변장하고 들어왔다면
You're okay, right?
괜찮아요?
Ba Bi will.. - Hang in there.
바비가.. - 조금만 참으세요.
- What's that? - What's that sound?
- 그게 뭐죠? - 그게 무슨 소리야?
What is that?
저게 뭐에요?
- What is that? - It's a stone fastball!* (T/N: means to be straightforward)
- 저게 뭐에요? - 돌직구다!* (T/N: 직구라는 뜻)
Ba Bi's strategy of attack is to be straightforward.
바비의 공격 전략은 간단명료하다.
That band is busking in Ilsan. Do you want to go with me?
그 밴드가 일산에서 버스킹을 하고 있어요. 나와 함께 갈래?
I don't know if I can...
할 수 있을지 모르겠어요...
You can.
당신은 할 수 있습니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
You're someone whom I always want to get to know.
당신은 내가 항상 알고 싶은 사람입니다.
That's why I want to be with you.
그래서 나는 당신과 함께 있고 싶습니다.
I'm saying that we should date.
우리 데이트하자고 말하는 거야.
- It's coming again. - Be careful! It's a very
- 또 오고 있어요. - 조심하세요! 정말
straightforward comment! ♫ Everyday higher than the sky there ♫.
솔직한 댓글! ♫ 매일 그곳의 하늘보다 높이 ♫.
♫  My heart wants to express everything to you  ♫.
♫ 내 마음은 당신에게 모든 것을 표현하고 싶어 ♫.
I'm so glad.
정말 기쁘다.
♫  Every day  ♫
♫ 매일 ♫
I'm so glad that you waited for me.
기다려주셔서 정말 기뻐요.
♫ My heart wants to express everything to you  ♫
♫ 내 마음은 당신에게 모든 것을 표현하고 싶어 ♫
I also want to know more about you.
나는 또한 당신에 대해 더 알고 싶습니다.
What?
무엇?
I also like you.
나도 당신을 좋아해요.
♫  Everyday. Oh ♫
♫ 매일. 아 ♫
♫  Everyday  ♫
♫ 매일 ♫
♫  and clear your clouds away Everyday  ♫
♫ 구름을 치우고 매일매일 ♫
Then, I...
그럼 난...
♫  Everyday higher than the sky there  ♫
♫ 매일 그곳의 하늘보다 높이 ♫
I'm going to go now.
나는 지금 갈 예정이다.
Can we start now then?
그럼 이제 시작해도 될까요?
Now, here?
자, 여기요?
What?
무엇?
Start what?
무엇을 시작할까요?
Dating.
데이트.
And in the end...
그리고 결국...
♫ A room without space to take a step ♫
♫ 한 발짝도 디딜 공간이 없는 방 ♫
This time, there are so many!
이번에는 정말 많아요!
♫ With only dust flying under the light bulb ♫
♫ 전구 아래에는 먼지만 날리며 ♫
Ba Bi's straightforwardness finally destroyed the Gate of Heart and the village succumbed.
바비의 솔직함은 마침내 마음의 문을 파괴했고 마을은 굴복했다.
We, the members of the Yu Ba Bi Club, call for Love.
우리 유바비클럽 회원들은 사랑을 외칩니다.
Our feelings for Yu Ba Bi is not fanship anymore!
유바비를 향한 우리의 마음은 더 이상 팬십이 아닙니다!
Is not fanship anymore!
더 이상 팬십이 아니다!
Love should yield! Accept Yu Ba Bi!
사랑은 양보해야합니다! 유바비를 받아들여라!
Accept Yu Ba Bi!
유바비를 받아들여라!
Yumi's boyfriend is now Yu Ba Bi!
유미의 남자친구는 이제 유바비입니다!
Love Ba Bi!
바비 사랑해!
- Love Ba Bi! - Love, you heard the news, right? The Gate of Heart has been destroyed.
- 바비를 사랑해요! - 사랑아, 소식 들었지? 마음의 문이 파괴되었습니다.
I heard. Do you see that?
들었어. 저거 보이나요?
Yu Ba Bi club members are protesting for me to yield–
유바비 동아리 회원들이 양보하라고 항의하고 있어요-
Don't tell me... you too?
말하지 마세요... 당신도요?
I just...
난 그냥...
It's funny right? I am wearing the Ba Bi T-shirt.
재미있지 않나요? 저는 Ba Bi 티셔츠를 입고 있어요.
We decided to date him anyway.
어쨌든 우리는 그와 데이트하기로 결정했습니다.
How can all of you do this without my permission?
내 허락 없이 어떻게 너희 모두가 이런 일을 할 수 있니?
Of course. Your opinion matters the most.
물론. 귀하의 의견이 가장 중요합니다.
If you say no, it's a no.
아니오라고 말하면 아니오입니다.
That's why even though the village has already been taken over, we haven't put up a white flag of surrender yet.
그렇기 때문에 마을은 이미 점령됐음에도 불구하고 우리는 아직 항복의 백기를 걸지 않은 것입니다.
We started dating but since it's not love yet.
우리는 연애를 시작했지만 아직은 사랑이 아니기 때문에.
Do you also want Yumi to love someone?
당신도 유미가 누군가를 사랑하길 바라나요?
About that... Honestly, I don't think it'll be easy to meet a guy like Yu Ba Bi again.
그런 건... 솔직히 유바비 같은 남자 다시 만나기 쉽지 않을 것 같아요.
He's handsome, gentle, has similar tastes and he likes Yumi.
잘생겼고, 젠틀하고, 취향도 비슷하고, 유미를 좋아한다.
Oh, also we got a call from Yumi's Healthcare Headquarters.
아, 그리고 유미 헬스케어 본부에서도 전화가 왔어요.
The graph looks great these days.
요즘 그래프가 참 좋네요.
She has maintained high self-esteem since she started dating him.
그녀는 그와 데이트를 시작한 이후로 높은 자존감을 유지해 왔습니다.
Thanks to Ba Bi, Yumi's mental health has improved.
바비 덕분에 유미의 정신 건강이 좋아졌습니다.
Of course we don't have to rush anything as they are still getting to know each other.
물론 아직 서로를 알아가고 있는 단계이기 때문에 서두를 필요는 없습니다.
Reason, I am afraid that I will get hurt again.
이유야, 또 상처받을까 두렵다.
If that happens, then I really won't be able to wake up again.
그렇게 되면 정말 다시는 깨어나지 못할 것 같아요.
Right, that shouldn't happen.
그렇죠, 그런 일은 일어나서는 안 됩니다.
- Then I'll go tell the guys to stop– - But this is the first time this has happened.
- 그럼 내가 가서 애들한테 그만하라고 할게- -그런데 이런 일은 처음이에요.
I'm talking about the village yielding.
나는 마을이 양보하는 것에 대해 이야기하고 있습니다.
This is how we started dating Ba Bi. [Yield]
이렇게 바비와 연애를 시작하게 됐어요. [수율]
It wasn't Love's decision but because of the haphazard straightforward attacks and the village yielding.
러브의 결정이 아니라, 닥치는 대로의 직격탄과 마을의 굴복 때문이었다.
Look there! Love accepted it!
저기 봐! 사랑은 그것을 받아들였습니다!
Love accepted Ba Bi!
사랑은 바비를 받아들였습니다!
She did. It's a success!
그녀는 그랬다. 성공이에요!
It was a white flag surrender everyone was happy about, except Love.
사랑을 제외하고 모두가 기뻐하는 백기 항복이었습니다.
Assistant Manager Yumi. This is last year's promotion project proposal you asked for.
유미 대리. 고객님께서 요청하신 작년 홍보사업 제안서입니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
2020 Promotion Project
2020년 홍보사업
Ah, yes.
아, 그렇죠.
You also printed out all the attached images.
첨부된 이미지도 모두 인쇄했습니다.
- Yes, I thought you might need it. - Thank you.
- 네, 필요할 수도 있겠다고 생각했어요. - 감사합니다.
Sure. Good luck.
확신하는. 행운을 빌어요.
Do you want to go to Paju today?
오늘 파주에 갈래?
I know a really good place in Paju. I think you will like it.
제가 파주에 정말 좋은 곳을 알고 있어요. 나는 당신이 그것을 좋아할 것이라고 생각합니다.
- Sounds good. Where is it? - A publishing complex...
- 좋은 것 같아요. 어디입니까? - 출판 단지...
It's a reliable option,
믿을 수 있는 옵션이에요,
but regarding the location, I'll coordinate and give you feedback again.
하지만 위치에 관해서는 제가 다시 조율해서 피드백 드리겠습니다.
If you send me your ideas of the information through email, I will take a look.
이메일을 통해 정보에 대한 아이디어를 보내주시면 살펴보겠습니다.
Okay, I will. Oh, and for the meeting time
알았어, 그럴게. 아, 그리고 회의 시간에는
let's set it for 6:10 pm for now.
지금은 오후 6시 10분으로 설정하겠습니다.
- All right. I got it. - Okay.
- 괜찮은. 알겠어요. - 좋아요.
- Goodbye. - Bye.
- 안녕히 가세요. - 안녕.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
- You did a good job today. - Same to you both.
- 오늘 정말 수고하셨어요. - 너희 둘 다 마찬가지야.
Oh my gosh. Why is it so cold? It's really going to be the end of the year soon.
맙소사. 왜 이렇게 추워요? 이제 정말 곧 연말이군요.
Are we going to be lonely again this Christmas?
이번 크리스마스에도 우리는 또 외로울까?
I'm so sick of it.
정말 지겨워요.
Eonni, don't say things like that. It's so annoying.
언니, 그런 말은 하지 마세요. 너무 짜증나네요.
It's okay. At least this year it's not the two of us but the three of us.
괜찮아요. 적어도 올해는 우리 둘이 아니라 우리 셋이에요.
- You're right. - I feel reassured because Yumi joined us.
- 당신 말이 맞아요. - 유미가 합류해서 든든해요.
- Let's be all together, Yumi. - You have to join us.
- 모두 함께하자, 유미. - 당신도 우리와 함께해야 해요.
- Eonni, I'm going to get going now. - Okay.
-언니 나 이제 가볼게. - 좋아요.
- Oh! I'll go with you. I have to go to the mall. I want to take the subway.
- 오! 나는 당신과 함께 갈 것이다. 나는 쇼핑몰에 가야 해요. 지하철을 타고 싶어요.
- We're going. - Bye.
- 우리는 간다. - 안녕.
Ba Bi got a new car last week and we commute to and from work together every day.
바비는 지난주에 새 차를 구입해 매일 같이 출퇴근하고 있어요.
- Were you waiting long? - I just got here.
- 오래 기다리셨나요? - 방금 도착했어요.
- I'm hungry. - What should we eat?
- 배고파요. - 우리는 무엇을 먹어야 할까요?
I like everything. You said we're going to Paju, right?
나는 모든 것을 좋아한다. 우리 파주로 간다고 했죠?
If we're going to Paju, then I know a really good place.
파주에 가신다면 제가 정말 좋은 곳을 알고 있어요.
- Then should we go there? - Do you want to go there?
- 그럼 우리 거기로 갈까? - 거기로 가고 싶나요?
Let's go there.
거기로 가자.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
This place is really good.
이곳은 정말 좋은 곳이에요.
I can tell just by looking at it.
딱 봐도 알 수 있어요.
- What can I get you? - Two servings of sundae (blood sausage), please.
- 무엇을 드릴까요? - 순대 2인분 주세요.
Do you want me to mix in the entrails?
내장에 섞어 드릴까요?
Of course! Mix it in.
물론! 섞어주세요.
The liver and lungs!
간과 폐!
Mix, mix.
섞고, 섞으세요.
What are you doing? Hurry and tell her to mix it in.
뭐하세요? 서둘러서 섞으라고 하세요.
Entrails. An animal's internal organs.
내장. 동물의 내부 장기.
Why does that sound disgusting today?
오늘은 왜 역겹게 들리나요?
Isn't liver and lungs a bit too much to eat in front of Ba Bi?
바비 앞에서 먹기에는 간과 폐가 좀 과한 것 아닌가?
Then ask for some ear and heart.
그런 다음 귀와 마음을 구하십시오.
That's even more disgusting.
그게 더 역겹네요.
Don't order entrails. Our Ba Bi doesn't eat entrails.
내장을 주문하지 마십시오. 우리 바비는 내장을 먹지 않아요.
How do you know if he eats it or not?
그 사람이 그것을 먹는지 안 먹는지 어떻게 알 수 있나요?
Look at him. He doesn't look like he would eat entrails.
그를보세요. 내장을 먹을 것 같지는 않네요.
Then does Yumi look like she enjoys eating entrails?
그렇다면 유미는 내장을 즐겨먹는 것 같나요?
Do you want to go to jail?
감옥에 가고 싶나요?
What do you want to do? Mix in the entrails?
무엇을 하고 싶나요? 내장을 섞나요?
Excuse me?
실례합니다?
Do you eat entrails?
내장을 먹나요?
- Huh? - Say you don't. It's the early stages of dating right now.
- 뭐? - 그렇지 않다고 말해요. 지금은 연애 초기 단계에요.
Don't scare off our Ba Bi.
우리 바비를 겁주지 마세요.
- I... - Okay. That's enough.
- 나는... - 알았어. 그것으로 충분합니다.
Yu Ba Bi club, I inform you that
유바비클럽 알려드립니다
our Sundae Entrails club respects all types of sundae preferences.
우리 순대 내장 클럽은 모든 유형의 순대 선호도를 존중합니다.
It doesn't matter if you don't order the entrails but!
내장은 주문하지 않으셔도 상관없지만!
We can't forgive you for disguising Yumi's preferences!
유미의 취향을 위장한 것은 용서할 수 없습니다!
I ...
나는 ...
do like it but if you don't eat it we can leave it out.
좋아하지만 안 먹으면 놔둬도 돼요.
- Mix it with the entrails. And add a lot of liver, please. - Sure.
- 내장과 섞어주세요. 그리고 간도 많이 넣어주세요. - 확신하는.
I like liver. What do you like?
나는 간을 좋아한다. 당신은 무엇을 좋아하나요?
- The lungs and ears. - I like your tastes.
- 폐와 귀. - 당신 취향이 좋아요.
Please add a lot of lungs and ears too.
폐와 귀도 많이 추가해주세요.
It really looks good.
정말 좋아 보인다.
Two hot Americanos, please.
따뜻한 아메리카노 두 잔 주세요.
Are you going to have them here?
여기에서 가져갈 건가요?
Should we drink them in the car?
차 안에서 마셔야 할까요?
Sounds good.
좋은 것 같아요.
- We'll take it to go. - Okay.
- 가져가겠습니다. - 좋아요.
Be careful, it's steep.
조심하세요. 경사가 심해요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Today I had the best sundae I've ever eaten.
오늘은 내가 먹어본 순대 중 최고로 맛있었습니다.
- Right? Wasn't it good? - Especially the ear.
- 오른쪽? 좋지 않았나요? - 특히 귀.
The ears are special. The ears are–
귀는 특별해요. 귀는-
Oh my! Oh my!
이런! 이런!
Oh no!
안 돼!
98, 99...
98, 99...
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Yes.
예.
That could have been bad.
그것은 나빴을 수도 있습니다.
Uh...
어...
Uh... I guess we need to reorder our coffee.
어... 커피를 다시 주문해야 할 것 같아요.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
No, it's okay.
아니요, 괜찮아요.
- Are you tired? - No.
- 피곤해요? - 아니요.
Then, should we stop by Heyri?
그럼 헤이리한테 들러볼까?
- Heyri? - It's a book café with a good vibe that I know.
- 헤이리? - 제가 아는 분위기 좋은 북카페예요.
- Is it too late? - No, sounds good.
- 너무 늦었나요? - 아뇨, ​​좋은 것 같아요.
Is it far from here?
여기서 먼가요?
It's close. About five minutes by car.
가깝습니다. 차로 약 5분.
It's close.
가깝습니다.
Do you want one?
하나 원하시나요?
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
Just candy.
그냥 사탕.
I'll get going.
나는 갈 것이다.
It's mint flavored. But why give me candy out of the blue?
민트맛이에요. 그런데 왜 갑자기 사탕을 주나요?
Tongue cell, what are you doing?
혀세포야, 뭐하는 거야?
I'm showering with candy. Ba Bi gave it to me.
나는 사탕으로 샤워를 하고 있어요. 바비가 나한테 줬어.
I see. Did he give it to us because the cake from earlier was rich?
알겠어요. 아까 먹은 케이크가 맛있다고 우리한테 준 걸까?
Yes. As usual, he's kind.
예. 평소처럼 그는 친절해요.
All right. How far did we go last time?
괜찮은. 지난번에 우리는 얼마나 멀리 갔나요?
Up to Chapter 2: Holding Hands.
2장: 손 잡기까지.
Then, today we are going over chapter 3.
그럼 오늘은 3장을 살펴보겠습니다.
Chapter 3: Kiss.
3장: 키스.
K I S S.
K I S S.
Kiss.
키스.
You're in your boyfriend's car and he gives you a mint candy.
당신은 남자친구의 차 안에 있고 그는 당신에게 민트사탕을 줍니다.
What does this mean?
이것은 무엇을 의미합니까?
- It means "Let's kiss!" - What?
- "키스하자!"라는 뜻이에요. - 무엇?
That's what it meant? I didn't know.
그게 무슨 뜻이야? 나는 몰랐다.
Calm down.
진정하다.
We've passed the age to make a fuss about this now.
이제 이걸 가지고 소란을 피울 나이는 지났습니다.
I mean it's too fast though.
그래도 너무 빠르단 말이에요.
This seems too fast. I mean... I couldn't even have imagined this–
너무 빠른 것 같습니다. 내 말은... 이건 상상도 못 한 일이군요.
I don't think that's it.
내 생각엔 그게 아닌 것 같아.
Ba Bi is a gentleman. It's only been a week since they started dating.
Ba Bi는 신사입니다. 사귄 지 이제 일주일 정도 됐어요.
Exactly.
정확히.
Is Ba Bi not a man? These guys!
바비는 남자 아니야? 이 녀석들!
- They had dinner, chewed gum, and drank coffee! - That's right.
- 저녁을 먹고, 껌을 씹고, 커피를 마셨어요! - 좋아요.
Then what does it mean when he gives her candy now?!
그렇다면 지금 그가 그녀에게 사탕을 준다는 것은 무슨 뜻일까요?!
Then when this candy finishes melting...
그럼 이 사탕이 다 녹으면...
He said we'd arrive in five minutes.
그는 우리가 5분 안에 도착할 것이라고 말했습니다.
So hurry and melt it.
그러니 빨리 녹여주세요.
Hurry, hurry!
서둘러, 서둘러!
Faster! Melt it faster!
더 빠르게! 더 빨리 녹여보세요!
Faster! Faster! Faster!
더 빠르게! 더 빠르게! 더 빠르게!
Help me!
도와주세요!
It doesn't melt well
잘 녹지 않아
It's really hard!
정말 어렵다!
So frustrating! Give it to me!
너무 실망 스럽습니다! 나에게 줘!
What to do!
무엇을 해야할지!
You prefer to chew candy.
당신은 사탕을 씹는 것을 더 좋아합니다.
You differ from me. I prefer to suck on it.
당신은 나와 다릅니다. 나는 그것을 빨아 먹는 것을 선호합니다.
Love, can you come down for a bit?
자기야, 잠깐 내려갈래?
I think everyone is overreacting. What do we do?
다들 과민반응하시는 것 같아요. 우리는 무엇을 합니까?
I've been watching.
나는 지켜보고 있었다.
Would Ba Bi really do that?
바비가 정말 그럴까요?
Ba Bi is a gentleman and has a calm and upright personality.
바비는 신사적이며 차분하고 올곧은 성격을 갖고 있다.
Who knows how Ba Bi feels?
바비의 기분이 어떤지 누가 알겠어요?
I'm questioning if Ba Bi is really a gentleman, calm, and upright person.
바비가 정말 신사적이고 차분하고 올바른 사람인지 궁금하네요.
- You're doubting it? - Yes.
- 의심하고 있나요? - 예.
I'm still apprehensive.
나는 아직도 불안하다.
If Ba Bi really likes Yumi and why he likes her.
바비가 유미를 정말 좋아하는지, 그리고 왜 그녀를 좋아하는지.
It's possible that Ba Bi was lonely after breaking up with his ex
바비는 전 애인과 헤어진 뒤 외로웠을 가능성이 있다
and chose Yumi.
그리고 유미를 선택했어요.
It could have been impulsive, right?
충동적이었을 수도 있겠죠?
Then what do we do?
그러면 우리는 무엇을 합니까?
We're here.
우리는 여기에 있습니다.
What?
무엇?
Huh?
뭐?
Are we getting out?
우리 나가는 거야?
Are we not?
우리는 그렇지 않습니까?
No, let's get out.
아니, 나가자.
♫ Let's build a little house in front of the river ♫
♫ 강 앞에 작은 집을 짓자 ♫
Uh... H-hold on. Really? ♫ Let's raise our dreams over the mountain peak there ♫
어... 잠깐만요. 정말? ♫ 저기 산봉우리 너머로 꿈을 키우자 ♫
♫ My dear ♫
♫ 내 사랑 ♫
What did I tell you? ♫ my dear ♫
내가 뭐라고 말했지?
Ba Bi is also a man, you idiots.
바비도 남자잖아 멍청아
♫ Let's hide in our little house and kiss ♫
♫ 우리 작은 집에 숨어 키스하자 ♫
♫ I will build a fortress in your heart when you have nowhere to go ♫
♫ 당신이 갈 곳이 없을 때 나는 당신의 마음에 요새를 세울 것입니다 ♫
♫ I will take it to you ♫
♫ 내가 가져갈게 ♫
♫ and open your door ♫
♫ 그리고 문을 열어라 ♫
♫ I will fill that boat ♫
♫ 그 배는 내가 채울 거야 ♫
♫ with luggage ♫
♫ 짐을 가지고 ♫
♫ It will carry our love ♫
♫ 그것은 우리의 사랑을 전달할 것입니다 ♫
♫  as the sun sets ♫
♫ 해가 지면서 ♫
♫ Even in the end your tears ♫
♫ 결국엔 너의 눈물도 ♫
That was fast. I never imagined that ♫ will be forgotten in the wind ♫
그것은 빨랐다. 그런 건 상상도 못했는데 ♫ 바람 속에 잊혀질 거예요 ♫
Ba Bi would open the wormhole this fast.
Ba Bi는 이렇게 빨리 웜홀을 열 것입니다.
This actually works out.
이것은 실제로 작동합니다.
I'm glad I got this opportunity so quickly.
이렇게 빨리 기회를 얻어서 기쁘다.
Love, where are you going?
사랑아, 어디 가니?
I'm going to Ba Bi's village.
바비 마을로 가겠습니다.
I need to see for myself what kind of person he is.
그 사람이 어떤 사람인지 직접 확인해봐야겠어요.
If he's a total jerk then it's better to get it together and end it quickly.
만약 그 사람이 완전 바보라면, 빨리 정리하고 끝내는 것이 낫습니다.
Love! Be careful!
사랑! 조심하세요!
Love, have a good trip!
사랑해요, 즐거운 여행 되세요!
Love is right.
사랑이 맞습니다.
A man who doesn't hesitate and has no self-control.
주저하지 않고 자제력이 없는 남자.
Ba Bi does seem like a really amazing guy but he also seems really dangerous.
바비는 정말 대단한 사람인 것 같으면서도 정말 위험한 사람인 것 같아요.
What kind of world is Ba Bi's world?
바비의 세계는 어떤 세계인가요?
Worst-case scenario he might be a sociopath.
최악의 경우 그는 소시오패스일 수도 있다.
Or it could be a terrible perverted world.
아니면 끔찍하고 변태적인 세상일 수도 있습니다.
What is that?
저게 뭐에요?
What's that?
그게 뭐야?
Hi, Yumi's Love cell.
안녕하세요 유미의 러브셀입니다.
Hi...
안녕하세요...
Hi, I'm Ba Bi's Reason cell.
안녕하세요 바비의 리즌셀 입니다.
Hi, I'm Ba Bi's Sensitivity cell.
안녕하세요 바비감성세포 입니다.
Hi, I'm Ba Bi's Love cell.
안녕하세요 바비의 러브셀 입니다.
We really wanted to meet you!
우리는 정말로 당신을 만나고 싶었습니다!
What is this...?
이게 뭔가요...?
While we were waiting for you we prepared a welcome song. Do you want to hear it?
여러분을 기다리는 동안 환영곡을 준비했습니다. 듣고 싶나요?
One, two, three.
하나 둘 셋.
♪ Welcome Welcome Welcome
♪ 환영합니다 환영합니다 환영합니다
♪ Welcome to Ba Bi's world! Hola!
♪ Ba Bi의 세계에 오신 것을 환영합니다! 안녕하세요!
♪ Welcome Yumi Nice to meet you Love cell ♪ Enjoy your time in our village
♪ 유미님 환영합니다 만나서 반가워요 러브셀 ♪ 우리 마을에서 즐거운 시간 보내세요
♪ There are a lot of fun things when Yumi and Ba Bi are together
♪ 유미와 바비가 함께하면 재미있는 일이 많아요
- ♪ This is Ba Bi's World! - Welcome!
- ♪ 여기는 바비의 세계! - 환영!
♪ This is Ba Bi's world
♪ 여기는 바비의 세상
♪ It's Ba Bi's world, Ba Bi's world Hola!
♪ 바비의 세상, 바비의 세상 Hola!
- Hola! - Gustar!
- 안녕하세요! - 구스타!
Gustar!
구스타!
It was a big surprise.
정말 놀랐습니다.
Ba Bi's world was neither gentle nor calm.
바비의 세계는 온화하지도, 고요하지도 않았다.
There was no artificial intelligence cell or algorithm. A totally new world.
인공지능 셀이나 알고리즘도 없었습니다. 완전히 새로운 세계.
We arrived in a new world
우리는 새로운 세계에 도착했어요
overflowing with roses, guitars, and romance.
장미와 기타, 그리고 낭만이 넘쳐요.
♫ Cause you're beautiful  ♫
♫ 당신은 아름다우니까요 ♫
♫ As much as I can't even breathe ♫
♫ 숨이 막힐 정도로 ♫
♫ I'm falling for you ♫
♫ 난 너에게 반해버렸어 ♫
♫ When I fall in love with you  ♫
♫ 내가 당신과 사랑에 빠졌을 때 ♫
♫  In my dreams which blossom ♫
♫ 꽃피는 꿈속에서 ♫
♫ You're there oh ♫
♫ 거기 있구나 ♫
♫ I have something to tell you  ♫
♫ 당신에게 할 말이 있어요 ♫
♫ I want to carefully come up to you ♫
♫ 조심스럽게 다가가고 싶어 ♫
♫ and whisper ♫
♫ 그리고 속삭임 ♫
♫ Everything about you oh ♫
♫ 당신에 관한 모든 것 오 ♫
♫ Everything about you ♫
♫ 당신에 관한 모든 것 ♫
♫ The moment our eyes met and captured each other ♫
♫ 눈이 마주치고 서로를 포착한 순간 ♫
♫ Everything becomes love oh ♫
♫ 모든 것이 사랑이 됩니다 오 ♫
♫ Everything becomes love ♫
♫ 모든 것이 사랑이 됩니다 ♫
♫ I wandered the universe ♫
♫ 나는 우주를 떠돌았어 ♫
♫ I found my earth ♫
♫ 내 지구를 찾았어 ♫
♫ You were heaven ♫
♫ 당신은 천국이었어요 ♫
♫ Because I don't know sometimes, I become impatient ♫
♫ 가끔은 모르기 때문에 조급해질 때도 있어요 ♫
♫ Show me how you feel ♫
♫ 기분이 어떤지 보여주세요 ♫
♫ My heart is about to explode ♫
♫ 가슴이 터질 것 같아 ♫
♫ When I'm next to you ♫
♫ 내가 네 옆에 있을 때 ♫
♫ Everything is made to match you ♫
♫ 모든 것이 당신에게 어울리도록 만들어졌습니다 ♫
♫ Everything about you oh ♫
♫ 당신에 관한 모든 것 오 ♫
♫ Everything about you ♫
♫ 당신에 관한 모든 것 ♫
♫ The moment our eyes met and captured each other ♫
♫ 눈이 마주치고 서로를 포착한 순간 ♫
Yumi's Cells 2 Preview
유미의 세포들 2 미리보기
Hi! Left. Right.
안녕! 왼쪽. 오른쪽.
Do you want to come to my place too?
너도 내 집에 올래?
You should be brave. With your skills, I'm sure you would have won something.
당신은 용감해야합니다. 당신의 기술이 있었다면 당신이 뭔가를 얻을 수 있었을 것이라고 확신합니다.
Really?
정말?
You might have become Writer Yumi.
당신은 유미 작가가 되었을지도 모릅니다.
That's crazy. I'm against it! I oppose.
정말 말도 안 되는 일이군요. 나는 반대한다! 나는 반대한다.
What do you think about sending Writer back to the grave first?
작가님을 먼저 무덤으로 돌려보내는 것에 대해 어떻게 생각하시나요?
This is unfair.
이것은 불공평합니다.
It's too late to have a dream.
꿈을 꾸기에는 너무 늦었습니다.
Really?
정말?
I want to try writing a novel.
소설을 써보고 싶어요.
That's a relief.
다행이네요.
♫ You were heaven ♫
♫ 당신은 천국이었어요 ♫